# VEDANT SOLANKI

SOFTWARE ENGINEER II

### **PERSONAL PROFILE**

SE II having 4+ years of experience in developing web and mobile applications specializing in Backend and API Development.

An inquisitive guy who loves Vi and Linux and who is interested in devising a better problemsolving method for challenging task and learning new technologies and tools if need arises.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: Python, JavaDatabases: MySQL, MongoDB

• Tools and Framework: Django, Git, Linux, SQLAlchemy

#### PERSONAL INTERESTS

- Photography
- Solo travelling
- Reading
- Sketching

#### Contact

Number: +91-9029408362 Email: lucifer.ved@gmail.com

Skype: ved.lucifer

linkedin:/in/vedantSolanki/

## **EDUCATION**

## Fr. Conceicao Rodrigues College of Engineering

B.E in Computer Engineering, May 2015

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Software Engineer II**

Visible Alpha, June 2017 - Present

- Designed and built module used by hedge fund analysts to understand deep forecast and historical data across multiple sector and industries.
- Designed and built automated service to parse XML file, scrape required data and feed it to database.
- Co-Developed web analytics tool for web application which logs user action and provide detailed information.
- Refactored traditional APIs with PubSub Service Integration.
- Contributed in Sharding activity to improve performance of the application.



# **Android Developer**

Godcast Messenger, Feb 2016 - June 2017

 Co-Developed broadcast messaging app on android along with server side functionality and infrastructure requirement.



## **Software Engineer Trainee**

Vistaar Technologies, June 2015 - Feb 2016

 Participated in developing one of the module of pricing management solution for one of the Fortune 500 company.



# **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

Autonomous Floor Sweeping Robot, Aug 2014 - June 2015

- · Reformed the way of cleaning dust from the floor.
- Sponsored by government of India and built to be used in "SWATCH BHARAT ABHIYAN"

M-Ticket, Jan 2014 - Sept 2014

- Tried to solve real life problem of Mumbai local railway.
- Implemented Ticket booking through mobile, using QR code and NFC.